Guide to the Oliver Reiser Papers, 1930-1974 UA.90.F10
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- Personal Papers, III.
  - Notebooks, 7.
    This subseries contains notebooks found among Reiser's papers. They are handwritten and appear to date from early in his life.
    - Black notebook (Box 13, Folder 815)
    - Four small notepads (Box 13, Folder 816)
    - Philosophy of Science Notebook (Box 13, Folder 817)
    - Realism Notebook (Box 13, Folder 818)
    - Symbolic Logic Notebook (Box 13, Folder 819)
  - Galleys, 8.
    This subseries contains galleys of other authors' books.
    - Commentary on The Single Reality (Box 12, Folder 823)
  - General, 9.
    This subseries contains disparate, non-note materials not organized by Reiser and not falling under other categories within Personal Papers. Folders Include articles, diagrams not discernably related to publications, magazines, newsletters, sheet music, monographs by other authors, and obituaries for Reiser. The section Oversize contains materials falling under this subseries but physically separate.
    - A Survey of Psychical Research in Europe (Jocelyn Pierson) (Box 9, Folder 748)
    - A.H. Maslow Papers (Box 9, Folder 749)
    - Alan Mayne Papers (Box 9, Folder 750)
    - American Humanist Association Papers (Box 9, Folder 751)
    - American Humanist Association's Notice of Reiser's 1969 Fellowship (Box 9, Folder 752)
    - Articles from Science (Box 9, Folder 753)
    - Articles from Scientific American (Box 9, Folder 754)
    - Articles on assorted subjects (1) (Box 9, Folder 755)
    - Articles on assorted subjects (2) (Box 9, Folder 756)
    - Articles on assorted subjects (3) (Box 9, Folder 757)
    - Articles on assorted subjects (4) (Box 9, Folder 758)
    - Articles on assorted Subjects (5) (Box 9, Folder 759)
    - Articles on assorted Subjects (6) (Box 9, Folder 760)
    - Articles on assorted subjects (7) (Box 10, Folder 761)
    - Articles on assorted subjects (8) (Box 10, Folder 762)
    - Articles on gravity (Box 10, Folder 763)
    - Articles on the hierarchical universe, quarks, and black holes (Box 10, Folder 764)
    - Artorga Newsletters (Box 10, Folder 765)
    - Assorted Magazines (1) (Box 10, Folder 766)
    - Awards received by Reiser (Box 10, Folder 767)
    - Awareness and Science (Edgar D Mitchell -- signed) (Box 10, Folder 768)
    - Book excerpts from Jerry Johnson (Box 10, Folder 769)
    - Book reviews of Reiser publications (Box 10, Folder 770)
    - Diagrams (inc. Infinite-Eternal Ocean of Energy) (Box 10, Folder 771)
    - Forecasting of the Future - Score Sheet (Box 10, Folder 772)
    - Frederic Gibbs Papers (Box 10, Folder 773)
    - Gustaf Stromberg Papers (Box 10, Folder 774)
    - Hudson Hoagland Papers (Box 10, Folder 775)
    - ICIS Center News Bulletin w/ notes (Box 10, Folder 776)
    - Integration -- Intellectual and Social (Box 10, Folder 777)
    - Issues of Main Currents of Modern Thought (1) (Box 10, Folder 778)
    - Issues of Main Currents of Modern Thought (2) (Box 10, Folder 779)
    - Issues of The Humanist (Box 10, Folder 780)
    - Issues of The Ley Hunter (Box 10, Folder 781)
    - James Benjamin Beal Papers (Box 10, Folder 782)
    - John Somerville Papers (Box 10, Folder 783)
    - Journal of Music Theory (Box 10, Folder 784)
    - Mark Braham Papers (Box 10, Folder 785)
    - National Industrial Conference Board Materials (Box 10, Folder 786)
    - Natural Major Scale Organization Diagram (Box 10, Folder 787)
    - New Age Library Folder, Glastonbury (Box 10, Folder 788)
    - New Age Library Folder, The Maltwood Story (Box 10, Folder 789)
    - Page from Model for a Universe w/ markings (Box 10, Folder 791)
    - Project Krishna Questions (Box 10, Folder 792)
    - "Proposal Concerning the Use of a Light/Sound Synthesis in the Conscious Elevation of Man's Awareness" (Box 10, Folder 793)
    - Quote from unidentified source beginning "In my half a century…" (Box 10, Folder 794)
    - Sheet Music for Robert Schumann's The Horseman (Box 11, Folder 795)
    - Societal Consequences of Changing Images of Man (Stanford Research Institute) (Box 11, Folder 796)
    - Sociological Notes on the Futurizing of the Multiversity (Arthur M. Harkins) (Box 11, Folder 797)
    - "Sources of Integrity in the Scientific Humanism of Oliver Reiser" (Box 11, Folder 798)
    - Synergy Newsletters (Box 11, Folder 799)
    - Time, Geometry and the Art of Seeing (Edgar Lipworth) (Box 11, Folder 800)
    - Translated Chapter of Die Philosophie der Gegenwart (Box 11, Folder 801)
    - Vaclav Hlavaty (Box 11, Folder 802)
    - W.F. Sutherland Notes on Paper by O.L. Reiser for A.A.A.S. (Box 11, Folder 803)
    - Reiser Obituaries (Box 11, Folder 803a)
    - Oversize
      - Arcosanti Drawing (Box 12, Folder 827)
      - Babel IIB Drawing (Box 12, Folder 828)
      - Envelope of Oversize Diagrams (Box 12, Folder 831)
      - Impressions from US Science Exhibit at Seattle World's Fair 1962 (Box 12, Folder 834)
      - Mercator Slide Rule Diagram (Box 12, Folder 835)
      - Map of Compton Dundon in Somerset, England (Box 12, Folder 836)
      - Biographical materials including photo (Box 12, Folder 838)
      - Adventures in the Realms of Thought (Cofman) (Box 13, Folder 825)
      - All the Way Round: Travel Diaries of Victor and Lucy Cofman 1948-1971 (Box 13, Folder 826)
      - The Book of the Baalshem Mishpat (Sonneborn) (Box 13, Folder 829)
      - Bound letters and images of artifacts with unattributed written commentary (Box 13, Folder 830)
      - Epitomization (Conger) (Box 13, Folder 832)
      - Humansitic Logic for the Mind in Action (Reiser) (Box 13, Folder 833)
      - Universities and the Quest for Peace: Final Report of the 1964 Africa and Middle East Conference (Box 13, Folder 837)
- Media, IV.
  The Media series contains recordings and a music slide rule.
  - Vinyl of Reiser Lecture on Scientific Humanism (Box 12, Folder 813)
  - E.W. Tipple's Music Slide Rule (Box 12, Folder 814)
  - Recording Tape "Dr Reiser C.W.S.C. 4/19/68" (Box 13, Folder 812)